( Watch on www.kissasia.co, .club, .be, .org, .net, .id, .xyz )
(شاهد على www.kissasia.co، .club، .be، .org، .net، .id، .xyz)
[Pursuit of Jade]
[السعي وراء اليشم]
[Episode 25]
[الحلقة 25]
It wasn't easy getting these pheasants today.
لم يكن من السهل اصطياد هذه الطيور اليوم.
I'll cook them later so everyone gets some meat.
سأقوم بطهيها لاحقاً حتى يحصل الجميع على بعض اللحم.
Let me handle this.
دعني أتولى الأمر.
You didn't pluck the feathers clean last time.
لم تقم بتنظيف الريش تمامًا في المرة الماضية.
The brothers said what you cooked wasn't good.
قال الإخوة إن ما طبخته لم يكن جيداً.
You tend the fire. Let me do it.
أنت تعتني بالنار. دعني أفعل ذلك.
Okay.
تمام.
You can't just use hot water to pluck pheasant feathers.
لا يمكنك استخدام الماء الساخن فقط لنتف ريش طائر التدرج.
You have to dip them in cold water first,
يجب غمسها في الماء البارد أولاً،
then scald them in hot water for half an incense stick's time.
ثم قم بغليها في الماء الساخن لمدة نصف مدة غلي عود البخور.
That's the only way to get them clean.
هذه هي الطريقة الوحيدة لتنظيفها.
You're quite the cook, young lady.
أنتِ طباخة ماهرة يا آنسة.
How about this?
ما رأيك بهذا؟
Come join our Mess Crew.
انضم إلى فريقنا في قسم الطعام.
I can't promise much else,
لا أستطيع أن أعد بأكثر من ذلك بكثير.
but as long as we have meat to eat,
لكن طالما لدينا لحم نأكله،
you'll get a share. What do you say?
ستحصل على حصة. ما رأيك؟
Thanks, Sir.
شكراً سيدي.
But I'll have to pass.
لكن عليّ أن أعتذر.
My husband is injured.
زوجي مصاب.
He needs someone to take care of him.
إنه بحاجة إلى شخص يعتني به.
Once he recovers,
بمجرد أن يتعافى،
I'll come help right away.
سآتي للمساعدة فوراً.
Sure!
بالتأكيد!
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Mrs. Fan.
السيدة فان.
Mr. Sun—
السيد صن—
No.
لا.
Mr. Counselor,
السيد المستشار،
do you need something?
هل تحتاج إلى شيء ما؟
Yes, I have something to tell you.
نعم، لدي شيء أريد أن أخبرك به.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Come, have a seat.
تفضل، اجلس.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
The soldiers built a new tent over there.
بنى الجنود خيمة جديدة هناك.
Yan Zheng has been moved there.
تم نقل يان تشنغ إلى هناك.
Really?
حقًا؟
It's quieter there,
المكان هناك أكثر هدوءاً،
so it's easier for you to brew his medicine.
لذلك يسهل عليك تحضير دوائه.
That's great.
هذا رائع.
But there are so many wounded.
لكن هناك الكثير من الجرحى.
Why move only him?
لماذا نقله هو فقط؟
Well,
حسنًا،
in the plan to flood the bandits,
في خطة إغراق قطاع الطرق،
you made a great contribution.
لقد قدمت مساهمة عظيمة.
You even risked your life to find your husband.
بل إنكِ خاطرتِ بحياتكِ للعثور على زوجكِ.
After the Marquis of Wu'an heard about it,
بعد أن سمع ماركيز ووآن بالأمر،
he gave this reward to your husband specifically.
لقد منح هذه المكافأة لزوجك تحديداً.
It was only a verbal reward?
هل كانت مجرد مكافأة لفظية؟
Nothing substantial?
لا شيء جوهري؟
There is!
هنالك!
This is yours.
هذا لك.
This isn't enough to share.
هذا لا يكفي للمشاركة.
That's not it.
هذا ليس هو.
Everyone in the pig butcher squad has a reward.
يحصل كل فرد في فرقة جزارة الخنازير على مكافأة.
E-Everyone?
إلكترونيًا للجميع؟
So much?
كثير جدًا؟
That's wonderful.
هذا رائع.
A powerful noble like the Marquis of Wu'an
نبيل قوي مثل ماركيز ووآن
actually keeps us commoners
في الواقع، هذا ما يجعلنا نحن عامة الناس
in mind.
في الاعتبار.
When Yan Zheng recovers,
عندما يتعافى يان تشنغ،
we'll go thank him together.
سنذهب لنشكره معاً.
That won't be necessary.
لن يكون ذلك ضرورياً.
I'll thank him properly on your behalf.
سأشكره كما ينبغي نيابةً عنك.
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
I have to go find that rascal Jiuheng
عليّ أن أذهب لأجد ذلك الوغد جيوينغ
to settle the score.
لتسوية الحساب.
One!
واحد!
Kill!
قتل!
Two!
اثنين!
One!
واحد!
Kill!
قتل!
Two!
اثنين!
This is the latest medicinal powder I developed.
هذا أحدث مسحوق طبي قمت بتطويره.
It's great for generating body fluids and stopping bleeding.
إنه رائع لتوليد سوائل الجسم ووقف النزيف.
[Regeneration and Bleed-Stop]
[التجديد ووقف النزيف]
I heard Your Highness tested hundreds of herbs
سمعت أن سموكم اختبر مئات الأعشاب
to find this non-toxic one.
لإيجاد هذا النوع غير السام.
On behalf of the soldiers,
نيابة عن الجنود،
I thank you, Your Highness.
أشكركم يا صاحب السمو.
It is my duty as a royal physician.
هذا واجبي كطبيب ملكي.
There is something I want to ask you.
هناك شيء أريد أن أسألك عنه.
Why are you deceiving Fan Changyu?
لماذا تخدع فان تشانغيو؟
Although she is a commoner,
على الرغم من أنها من عامة الشعب،
I can't bear to see such a nice lady suffer.
لا أطيق رؤية سيدة لطيفة كهذه تعاني.
Except for my identity as the Marquis of Wu'an,
باستثناء هويتي بصفتي ماركيز ووآن،
I haven't lied to her at all.
لم أكذب عليها إطلاقاً.
You should worry about yourself first.
يجب أن تهتم بنفسك أولاً.
Don't worry about my affairs.
لا تقلق بشأن شؤوني.
Your status as the Marquis of Wu'an is too different from hers.
مكانتك كماركيز ووآن تختلف كثيراً عن مكانتها.
Marquis of Wu'an?
ماركيز ووآن؟
What are you saying about the Marquis of Wu'an?
ماذا تقول عن ماركيز ووآن؟
Changyu.
تشانغيو.
Something about a status difference?
هل يتعلق الأمر باختلاف في المكانة الاجتماعية؟
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Did something happen?
هل حدث شيء ما؟
There's a status difference between Yan Zheng
هناك فرق في المكانة بين يان تشنغ
and the Marquis of Wu'an, right?
والماركيز من ووآن، أليس كذلك؟
He's teaching
إنه يُدرّس
the Marquis of Wu'an how to butter up to his wife
ماركيز ووآن: كيف يتملق زوجته
and keep a private stash.
واحتفظ بمخبأ خاص.
A private stash?
مخبأ خاص؟
The Marquis of Wu'an has a private stash too?
هل يمتلك ماركيز ووآن مخبأً خاصاً أيضاً؟
He's just like Mr. Zhao.
إنه يشبه السيد تشاو تماماً.
So you must keep a close eye on Yan Zheng.
لذا يجب عليك مراقبة يان تشنغ عن كثب.
If the Marchioness finds out,
إذا علمت الماركيزة بذلك،
he'll be in big trouble.
سيقع في مشكلة كبيرة.
Seriously.
بجد.
You're bad at lying to start with.
أنت سيء في الكذب أصلاً.
Why would you give the Marquis such an idea?
لماذا قد تعطي الماركيز مثل هذه الفكرة؟
All right.
حسنًا.
I shan't disturb you two lovebirds chatting.
لن أزعجكما أيها العاشقان أثناء حديثكما.
I'm off to brew medicine.
سأذهب الآن لتحضير الدواء.
The Mess Crew caught some pheasants.
اصطاد فريق الطبخ بعض طيور التدرج.
I bought one
اشتريت واحدة
to nourish your body.
لتغذية جسمك.
Here.
هنا.
It smells good.
رائحتها طيبة.
But without salt,
لكن بدون ملح،
it might be gamey.
قد يكون طعمه غريباً بعض الشيء.
Let me do it.
دعني أفعل ذلك.
Look.
ينظر.
What is this?
ما هذا؟
The Marquis knows about
يعرف الماركيز عن
how we intercepted scouts at Baxia.
كيف اعترضنا الكشافة في باكسيا.
He rewarded me and the pig butcher squad.
كافأني أنا وفريق جزارة الخنازير.
I have money now, so I can support you.
لديّ المال الآن، لذا يمكنني إعالتك.
That's good.
هذا جيد.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
when you came up the mountain, didn't you think about
عندما صعدت الجبل، ألم تفكر في
what if you couldn't get down?
ماذا لو لم تستطع النزول؟
The Marquis of Wu'an is so powerful;
إن ماركيز ووآن يتمتع بنفوذ كبير؛
he surely wouldn't let us die on the mountain.
من المؤكد أنه لن يسمح لنا بالموت على الجبل.
Even if the rebels really attack the mountain,
حتى لو هاجم المتمردون الجبل بالفعل،
I can take you to escape.
أستطيع أن آخذك إلى مكان للهروب.
If that time really comes,
إذا حان ذلك الوقت بالفعل،
just think about how to save yourself.
فكر فقط في كيفية إنقاذ نفسك.
Why bring me along?
لماذا اصطحبوني معكم؟
Why not?
ولم لا؟
I said I would support you,
قلتُ إنني سأدعمك،
and I definitely will.
وسأفعل ذلك بالتأكيد.
When you left Lin'an,
عندما غادرت لينان،
I hit you
لقد ضربتك
and said harsh words.
وقال كلمات قاسية.
Every time I think about it, I feel terrible
في كل مرة أفكر في الأمر، أشعر بالسوء الشديد.
and very guilty.
ومذنب للغاية.
You...
أنت...
You came to look for me
لقد أتيت لتبحث عني
just because you felt guilty?
لمجرد شعورك بالذنب؟
No, that's not it.
لا، ليس هذا هو الأمر.
I...
أنا...
I was not just guilty.
لم أكن مذنباً فحسب.
You have no idea.
ليس لديك أدنى فكرة.
On my way here,
في طريقي إلى هنا،
I almost died.
كادت أن أموت.
When Lin'an was massacred,
عندما وقعت مذبحة لينان،
that bastard came for revenge,
جاء ذلك الوغد للانتقام،
and I nearly fell off a cliff to my death.
وكدت أسقط من جرف وأموت.
Luckily,
لحسن الحظ،
a passing granny saved me.
أنقذتني جدة عابرة.
I'm not afraid of death.
أنا لا أخشى الموت.
But I am afraid Changning would be left without a sister.
لكنني أخشى أن تُترك تشانغنينغ بلا أخت.
And I am afraid I'd never see you again.
وأخشى ألا أراك مرة أخرى.
I missed you so much.
اشتقت إليك كثيراً.
I was so scared you were dead.
كنت خائفًا جدًا من أنك مت.
Don't die.
لا تموت.
Come home with me, okay?
تعال معي إلى المنزل، حسناً؟
Okay.
تمام.
I slept for so long.
نمت لفترة طويلة.
Wake me up next time.
أيقظني في المرة القادمة.
Sleep if you want to.
نم إن أردت.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
I remember
أتذكر
when I brought you home from the snow,
عندما أحضرتك إلى المنزل من الثلج،
you were much dirtier than you are now.
كنتَ أكثر اتساخاً مما أنت عليه الآن.
I couldn't make out
لم أستطع التمييز
your face with all the blood on it.
وجهك مغطى بالدماء.
Here.
هنا.
Now I've nursed you back to health.
لقد اعتنيت بك حتى شفيت تماماً.
Does it still hurt?
هل ما زال يؤلمك؟
With you here,
بوجودك هنا،
it's much better.
إنه أفضل بكثير.
Your hand.
يدك.
Changyu.
تشانغيو.
You kissed me.
لقد قبلتني.
I...
أنا...
Just now, I...
الآن فقط، أنا...
Now we're even.
الآن تعادلنا.
I'll come see you tomorrow morning.
سأزورك غداً صباحاً.
Get some rest.
خذ قسطاً من الراحة.
Shiny!
لامع!
It's heavy.
إنه ثقيل.
This Marquis of Wu'an is really generous.
إن ماركيز ووآن هذا كريم حقاً.
Here.
هنا.
Boss.
رئيس.
Big Brother.
الأخ الأكبر.
Did you find Changyu?
هل وجدت تشانغيو؟
Yes.
نعم.
That's good.
هذا جيد.
She found her matrilocal husband too.
وجدت زوجها الذي سيعيش معها في منزل والدتها أيضاً.
Really?
حقًا؟
Look.
ينظر.
So much money.
الكثير من المال.
Changyu is happy,
تشانغيو سعيد،
so I'm happy too.
لذا فأنا سعيد أيضاً.
Happy, happy.
سعيد، سعيد.
I think it's our turn to get lucky.
أعتقد أن دورنا قد حان لنحظى ببعض الحظ.
How so?
كيف ذلك؟
Look, Changyu found her husband,
انظروا، لقد وجدت تشانغيو زوجها،
we got the reward money,
حصلنا على مكافأة مالية،
and there's another living soul in Lin'an.
وهناك روح حية أخرى في لينآن.
What's that phrase again?
ما هي تلك العبارة مرة أخرى؟
What phrase?
ما العبارة؟
The one where everyone wins.
تلك التي يفوز فيها الجميع.
Everyone wins?
الجميع فائز؟
A win-win situation.
وضع مربح للجميع.
Right!
يمين!
You're so educated.
أنت مثقف جداً.
So educated.
مثقف جداً.
It didn't even come to my mind.
لم يخطر ببالي ذلك حتى.
As expected.
كما هو متوقع.
If you ask me,
إذا سألتني،
-There's a reason why you can succeed. -What's with the noise so late at night?
- هناك سببٌ وراء قدرتك على النجاح. - ما هذا الضجيج في وقت متأخر من الليل؟
Are you going to let people sleep or not?
هل ستسمح للناس بالنوم أم لا؟
Why... Why is it you guys again?
لماذا... لماذا أنتم بالذات؟
It's you again, isn't it?
أنت مرة أخرى، أليس كذلك؟
Come back.
عد.
Go back.
عُد.
Come on. Cheers.
هيا بنا. تحياتي.
Here.
هنا.
Changyu.
تشانغيو.
Sister, I'm cold.
يا أختي، أشعر بالبرد.
Here.
هنا.
Cover up.
التستر.
He's so badly injured.
إنه مصاب بجروح بالغة.
How can he still go to the battlefield?
كيف لا يزال بإمكانه الذهاب إلى ساحة المعركة؟
I'm freezing to death.
أنا أتجمد حتى الموت.
She might as well sleep with Brother-in-Law.
ربما من الأفضل لها أن تنام مع صهرها.
[Xie]
[شيه]
Counselor!
مستشار!
Her High—
ذروتها—
The Royal Physician, she...
الطبيبة الملكية، هي...
What happened to her?
ماذا حدث لها؟
Quick!
سريع!
Your Highness!
يا صاحب السمو!
Jianjia, this prescription works wonders for internal injuries.
جيانجيا، هذه الوصفة الطبية فعالة للغاية في علاج الإصابات الداخلية.
Distribute it to the other medics immediately.
قم بتوزيعها على المسعفين الآخرين فوراً.
Tell them to brew it at once.
أخبرهم أن يقوموا بتحضيره على الفور.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Just to fiddle with these herbs,
مجرد تجربة هذه الأعشاب،
you ruin your health?
هل تدمر صحتك؟
I've tested them myself.
لقد اختبرتها بنفسي.
These herbs are non-toxic
هذه الأعشاب غير سامة
and can be found everywhere.
ويمكن العثور عليها في كل مكان.
You...
أنت...
You tested the medicine yourself?
هل اختبرت الدواء بنفسك؟
Her Highness has tested many kinds.
لقد اختبرت صاحبة السمو أنواعاً كثيرة.
She's almost lost her sense of taste.
كادت أن تفقد حاسة التذوق.
There's no salt in the army anyway.
لا يوجد ملح في الجيش على أي حال.
It's just as well.
هذا أفضل.
It saves me from tasting the gaminess.
فهو يجنبني تذوق الطعم البري.
The medicine is ready.
الدواء جاهز.
Go, Jianjia.
اذهب يا جيانجيا.
As the Princess Royal,
بصفتها الأميرة الملكية،
you are incredibly noble.
أنت نبيل للغاية.
How can you be so reckless?
كيف يمكنك أن تكون بهذه التهور؟
I am a royal physician now.
أنا طبيب ملكي الآن.
I came to this army to save people.
لقد انضممت إلى هذا الجيش لإنقاذ الناس.
Fine, even if you are a physician,
لا بأس، حتى لو كنت طبيباً.
the origin of these herbs is unknown.
أصل هذه الأعشاب غير معروف.
What if they are poisonous?
ماذا لو كانت سامة؟
-It can be fatal. -So what?
- قد يكون الأمر مميتاً. - وماذا في ذلك؟
I told you,
أخبرتك،
don't treat me as the Princess Royal.
لا تعاملوني كأميرة ملكية.
Headmaster, you are not a teacher at the academy here.
يا مدير المدرسة، أنت لست معلماً في هذه الأكاديمية.
In what capacity are you questioning me?
بأي صفة تستجوبني؟
Back at the academy,
بالعودة إلى الأكاديمية،
didn't you say,
ألم تقل ذلك؟
"A ruler must bear the burden of protecting the common people"?
"يجب على الحاكم أن يتحمل عبء حماية عامة الشعب"؟
A ruler must bear the burden of protecting the common people.
يجب على الحاكم أن يتحمل عبء حماية عامة الشعب.
A ruler of a nation
حاكم أمة
must shoulder the heavy responsibility
يجب أن يتحمل المسؤولية الجسيمة
of protecting the people of the world.
حماية شعوب العالم.
That is the way of the ruler and minister.
هذا هو نهج الحاكم والوزير.
The Princess Royal is of noble birth
الأميرة الملكية من أصل نبيل
and a woman.
وامرأة.
Why be so harsh on yourself?
لماذا تقسو على نفسك هكذا؟
Precisely because I bear the duties of the Princess Royal
وذلك تحديداً لأنني أتحمل واجبات الأميرة الملكية
and enjoy the blessings of the people,
وأن يتمتع بنعم الناس،
I have even more responsibility and obligation to protect them.
لدي مسؤولية والتزام أكبر لحمايتهم.
Don't I?
أليس كذلك؟
This way,
من هنا،
the soldiers' pain can be alleviated,
يمكن تخفيف آلام الجنود،
and for this battle,
وفي هذه المعركة،
there is hope of winning.
هناك أمل في الفوز.
Your Highness, drink the medicine.
يا صاحب السمو، اشرب الدواء.
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Her Highness tests herbs daily, so being poisoned is inevitable.
تقوم صاحبة السمو بفحص الأعشاب يومياً، لذا فإن التسمم أمر لا مفر منه.
This is the antidote soup Her Highness prepared in advance.
هذا هو حساء الترياق الذي أعدته صاحبة السمو مسبقاً.
Let me.
دعني.
It seems
يبدو
you're not stupid after all.
أنت لست غبياً في النهاية.
You knew to prepare an antidote for yourself.
كنتَ تعلم أن تُحضّر لنفسك ترياقاً.
Here.
هنا.
Who are you calling stupid?
من تصفه بالغباء؟
I'm stupid.
أنا غبي.
Here.
هنا.
I'm stupid, I'm stupid.
أنا غبي، أنا غبي.
Slowly.
ببطء.
That wretched girl who delivered the grain,
تلك الفتاة البائسة التي أوصلت الحبوب،
she's the dame the Heir Apparent ordered
إنها السيدة التي أمر بها ولي العهد
to be captured alive.
أن يتم القبض عليه حياً.
This dame is not simple.
هذه السيدة ليست بسيطة.
She killed three of our scouts
قتلت ثلاثة من كشافةنا
and even stabbed the Heir Apparent.
بل وطعن ولي العهد.
She's ruthless and incredibly bold.
إنها قاسية وجريئة بشكل لا يصدق.
If I'd known, I would have ambushed that grain convoy myself.
لو كنت أعلم، لكنت نصبت كميناً لقافلة الحبوب بنفسي.
I missed a good chance to earn merit for nothing.
أضعت فرصة جيدة لكسب الفضل دون مقابل.
Hu.
هو.
Remember this.
تذكر هذا.
As long as the Heir Apparent is in their hands,
طالما أن ولي العهد في أيديهم،
we cannot act rashly.
لا يمكننا التصرف بتهور.
How long must we swallow this till?
إلى متى سنظل نتحمل هذا الوضع؟
The Old Prince is still waiting for us
لا يزال الأمير العجوز ينتظرنا
to meet up in Lucheng!
لنلتقي في لوتشنغ!
Of course we won't swallow it forever.
بالطبع لن نبتلعه إلى الأبد.
But to deal with the Marquis of Wu'an,
لكن للتعامل مع ماركيز ووآن،
we have to outsmart them.
علينا أن نتفوق عليهم ذكاءً.
A brute attack will only end in a loss.
لن يؤدي الهجوم العنيف إلا إلى الخسارة.
Let's surround them and break their spirit.
فلنحاصرهم ونكسر عزيمتهم.
Once their army morale crumbles,
بمجرد أن تنهار معنويات جيشهم،
we'll seize the chance to attack.
سنغتنم الفرصة للهجوم.
But what about the Heir Apparent's safety—
لكن ماذا عن سلامة ولي العهد؟
We have to wait for the Marquis of Wu'an to lower his guard;
علينا أن ننتظر حتى يخفف ماركيز ووآن من حذره؛
only then can we rescue the Heir Apparent.
عندها فقط يمكننا إنقاذ ولي العهد.
Go!
يذهب!
Hurry!
عجل!
Faster. Fall in.
أسرع. انغمس.
Why are we gathering so early in the morning?
لماذا نجتمع في هذا الوقت المبكر من الصباح؟
Do you smell that aroma?
هل تشمّ تلك الرائحة؟
It smells like roast meat.
رائحته تشبه رائحة اللحم المشوي.
Oh my god, it smells so good.
يا إلهي، رائحته رائعة للغاية.
It smells so good.
رائحته جميلة جداً.
Give me one.
أعطني واحدة.
Come on.
تعال.
It smells so good.
رائحته جميلة جداً.
It's been ages since I had meat.
لقد مر وقت طويل منذ أن تناولت اللحم.
Roast meat?
لحم مشوي؟
Where is it? Find it.
أين هو؟ ابحث عنه.
Where?
أين؟
Here.
هنا.
[Regeneration and Bleed-Stop]
[التجديد ووقف النزيف]
Jiu—
جيو—
Yan Zheng.
يان تشنغ.
Come in. No one's here.
تفضل بالدخول. لا أحد هنا.
Good news.
أخبار سارة.
After you asked the soldiers at the foot of the mountain
بعد أن سألت الجنود عند سفح الجبل
to scrape tree bark and dig tree roots,
لكشط لحاء الأشجار وحفر جذورها،
they really fell for the trap.
لقد وقعوا في الفخ بالفعل.
They all thought we're out of food in the mountain.
ظنوا جميعاً أن طعامنا قد نفد في الجبل.
Now, to the east and south of the hill,
والآن، إلى الشرق والجنوب من التل،
they're roasting lamb.
إنهم يشوون لحم الضأن.
and want to dampen our soldiers' morale with that.
ويريدون بذلك إضعاف معنويات جنودنا .
Shi Yue is pretty smart
شي يو ذكي جداً
for thinking of that.
لتفكيرك في ذلك.
They're underestimating us.
إنهم يستهينون بنا.
The men of Yanzhou have backbone.
رجال يانتشو يتمتعون بالشجاعة.
Even if we didn't have food,
حتى لو لم يكن لدينا طعام،
and had to eat roots and bark,
وكان عليه أن يأكل الجذور واللحاء،
we wouldn't surrender to those rebels
لن نستسلم لهؤلاء المتمردين
because of such cheap tricks.
بسبب هذه الحيل الرخيصة.
He has brains, but not much.
لديه عقل، لكن ليس كثيراً.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Proceed as planned.
استمر كما هو مخطط له.
-Yes, Sir.
- نعم سيدي.
Do you smell it?
هل تشمّها؟
What's that smell?
ما هذه الرائحة؟
Where is that roast meat smell coming from?
من أين تأتي رائحة اللحم المشوي هذه ؟
It smells so good.
رائحته جميلة جداً.
I'm so hungry.
أنا جائع جداً.
Hurry up, hurry.
أسرع، أسرع.
Hurry up.
أسرع.
Sorry.
آسف.
Sir.
سيد.
Do you know where the men from the light injury camp went?
هل تعلم أين ذهب الرجال من معسكر الإصابات الطفيفة؟
The rebels are roasting lamb down the hill.
يقوم المتمردون بشواء لحم الضأن أسفل التل.
The whole camp is on alert.
المعسكر بأكمله في حالة تأهب.
Those in the light injury camp...
أولئك الذين يعانون من إصابات طفيفة...
must have been summoned urgently.
لا بد أنه تم استدعاؤه على وجه السرعة.
They've gone to fight again?
هل ذهبوا للقتال مرة أخرى؟
Their wounds haven't even healed.
لم تلتئم جراحهم بعد.
Sir.
سيد.
Do you know where they are going to fight?
هل تعلم أين سيقاتلون؟
I don't.
أنا لا.
Prying into military secrets
التطفل على الأسرار العسكرية
can get you beheaded.
قد يؤدي ذلك إلى قطع رأسك.
I'm just worried about Yan Zheng's injury.
أنا قلق فقط بشأن إصابة يان تشنغ.
Your husband is capable.
زوجك كفؤ.
He's very skilled.
إنه ماهر للغاية.
He'll be fine.
سيكون بخير.
No matter how skilled he is,
بغض النظر عن مدى مهارته،
he's just a foot soldier.
إنه مجرد جندي عادي.
He'll always be on the front lines.
سيظل دائماً في الخطوط الأمامية.
Even if the Marquis of Wu'an is on the front lines,
حتى لو كان ماركيز ووآن في الخطوط الأمامية،
it's to protect everyone.
الهدف هو حماية الجميع.
Then I hope the Marquis of Wu'an can protect him.
إذن آمل أن يتمكن ماركيز ووآن من حمايته.
Changyu!
تشانغيو!
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
The cave...
الكهف...
In the cave...
في الكهف...
What about the cave? Speak slowly.
ماذا عن الكهف؟ تكلم ببطء.
That villain,
ذلك الشرير،
I saw him get caught.
رأيته يُقبض عليه.
They locked him in the cave.
قاموا بحبسه في الكهف.
Take care of Changning for me.
اعتني بشانغنينغ من أجلي.
Changning, who is this villain?
تشانغنينغ، من هذا الشرير؟
What did he do?
ماذا فعل؟
I saw him killing people in Xigu Lane.
رأيته يقتل الناس في زقاق شيغو.
Important prisoners are held here.
يتم احتجاز السجناء المهمين هنا.
No trespassing allowed.
ممنوع التعدي على الممتلكات الخاصة.
I just want to know
أريد فقط أن أعرف
if the one inside
إذا كان الشخص الموجود بالداخل
is that bastard named Sui.
هل هذا الوغد المسمى سوي؟
Is that Mrs. Fan out there?
هل تلك السيدة فان هناك؟
To think you'd come here.
يا للعجب أنك أتيت إلى هنا.
Our fate is indeed destined by heaven.
إن مصيرنا مكتوبٌ من السماء.
Did you come to catch up with me?
هل أتيت لتلحق بي؟
I'll kill you right now, you bastard!
سأقتلك الآن أيها الوغد!
Military orders are absolute.
الأوامر العسكرية مطلقة.
Do not make a mistake.
لا ترتكب خطأً.
I don't care about your orders.
لا أهتم بأوامرك.
My mother is dead.
توفيت والدتي.
Why should he live?
لماذا ينبغي أن يعيش؟
Wait!
انتظر!
Mrs. Fan.
السيدة فان.
I know why you are here.
أعرف لماذا أنت هنا.
But the prisoner held here
لكن السجين المحتجز هنا
is crucial to the entire war.
يُعدّ أمراً بالغ الأهمية للحرب بأكملها.
He is a risky pawn to check the enemy.
إنه بيدق محفوف بالمخاطر لكبح جماح العدو.
He can't die yet.
لا يمكنه أن يموت بعد.
I just want to ask him one thing.
أريد فقط أن أسأله شيئاً واحداً.
Why did he slaughter Lin'an Town?
لماذا قام بمذبحة بلدة لينان؟
Those innocent people...
هؤلاء الأبرياء...
what crime did they commit?
ما الجريمة التي ارتكبوها؟
Then come in.
ثم ادخل.
Come in and I'll tell you.
ادخل وسأخبرك.
I'll kill you.
سأقتلك.
Fine!
بخير!
But only you can come in with me alone.
لكن أنت وحدك من يستطيع الدخول معي بمفردنا.
Give me the sword.
أعطني السيف.
Open the door.
افتح الباب.
Yes.
نعم.
We meet again before the blood has even dried.
نلتقي مجدداً قبل أن يجف الدم.
Mrs. Fan.
السيدة فان.
I've been thinking about you every day.
أفكر فيك كل يوم.
What about you?
ماذا عنك؟
Did you miss me?
هل إفتقدتني؟
I miss you so much...
أفتقدك كثيرًا...
that I want you to die a horrible death.
أريدك أن تموت ميتة بشعة.
Why did you massacre Lin'an?
لماذا ارتكبت مذبحة لينان؟
Why?
لماذا؟
For no reason.
بلا سبب.
Didn't Xie Zheng want to protect Lin'an?
ألم يكن شيه تشنغ يريد حماية لينآن؟
I just wouldn't let him have his way.
لن أدعه يفعل ما يريد.
Anyone from Lin'an
أي شخص من لينان
must die.
يجب أن يموت.
Just out of spite?
هل كان ذلك بدافع الحقد فقط؟
The old, the weak, women, and children...
كبار السن، والضعفاء، والنساء، والأطفال...
you didn't spare a single one.
لم تترك أحداً دون أن تقتله.
They were just ants.
كانوا مجرد نمل.
Are you that angry?
هل أنت غاضب لهذه الدرجة؟
Then let me tell you more.
دعني أخبرك المزيد.
Your sister,
أختك،
the little girl
الفتاة الصغيرة
with Tuberculosis.
مصاب بالسل.
When I forced her to ride in front of me,
عندما أجبرتها على الركوب أمامي،
she couldn't stand the bumps,
لم تستطع تحمل المطبات،
she kept vomiting,
استمرت في التقيؤ،
I almost drowned her in the water.
كادت أن تغرق في الماء.
The look on her face...
نظرة وجهها...
was so entertaining.
كان الأمر مسلياً للغاية.
And that darn constable.
وذلك الشرطي اللعين.
He was so stubborn!
كان عنيداً جداً!
But he still died with one stab from me.
لكنه مع ذلك مات بطعنة واحدة مني.
As for the magistrate's daughter,
أما ابنة القاضي،
she refused to tell me where you were.
رفضت أن تخبرني بمكانك.
I showed no mercy.
لم أُظهر أي رحمة.
With one thrust of my spear,
بطعنة واحدة من رمحي،
her blood sprayed 3 chi high.
اندفع دمها بقوة ثلاثة أضعاف ارتفاع تشي.
Mrs. Fan!
السيدة فان!
Calm down!
اهدأ!
Come on!
تعال!
Do it!
افعلها!
Kill me!
اقتلني!
Mrs. Fan!
السيدة فان!
Hyah!
هيا!
Smells so good.
رائحته جميلة جداً.
Look at the fire.
انظر إلى النار.
It should be done, right?
ينبغي القيام بذلك، أليس كذلك؟
Here, take it.
تفضل، خذه.
Put it over there.
ضعه هناك.
Your Lordship, bad news.
يا صاحب السعادة، لدي أخبار سيئة.
Sui Yuanqing was taken away by Mrs. Fan.
أخذت السيدة فان سوي يوانكينغ بعيداً.
If you have the guts, make it quick.
إذا كنت تملك الشجاعة، فافعل ذلك بسرعة.
Just kill me now!
اقتلني الآن!
I won't let you off that easily.
لن أتركك تفلت بهذه السهولة.
You bunch of cowards.
يا مجموعة الجبناء.
Think you can avenge the people of Lin'an?
هل تعتقد أنك تستطيع الانتقام لأهل لينان؟
One more word,
كلمة أخيرة،
and I'll slaughter you right now.
وسأذبحك الآن.
His Lordship arranged this.
قام صاحب السمو بترتيب هذا الأمر.
Just watch.
شاهد فقط.
Let me go!
دعني أذهب!
Tie him tighter.
اربطه بإحكام.
Done.
منتهي.
Bandits!
قطاع طرق!
Open your dog eyes and look!
افتح عيون كلبك وانظر!
Your Heir Apparent
ولي عهدك
is in my hands!
الأمر بيدي!
Sir,
سيد،
it really is the Heir.
إنه الوريث بالفعل.
Should we save him?
هل يجب أن ننقذه؟
That is...
إنه...
Mrs. Fan?
السيدة فان؟
Ridiculous.
سخيف.
Could Xie Zheng have seen through my plan?
هل كان بإمكان شيه تشنغ أن يكتشف خطتي؟
Sir,
سيد،
why don't we lead troops
لماذا لا نقود القوات؟
to save the Heir Apparent
لإنقاذ ولي العهد
first?
أولاً؟
No.
لا.
Xie Zheng might be plotting something.
ربما يدبر شيه تشنغ شيئاً ما.
I'll take a squad
سأختار فرقة
and check the west side first.
وتفقد الجانب الغربي أولاً.
You stay here and keep luring the enemy.
ابقَ هنا واستمر في استدراج العدو.
Sound the horn.
أطلقوا البوق.
Sound the horn!
أطلقوا البوق!
What? Scared now?
ماذا؟ خائف الآن؟
If you're scared, let me down.
إذا كنت خائفاً، فأنزلني.
When my army comes up,
عندما يستعد جيشي،
I might leave your corpses intact.
قد أترك جثثكم سليمة.
Look.
ينظر.
Shi Yue moved first.
تحرك شي يو أولاً.
Why did he only take a small group?
لماذا اصطحب معه مجموعة صغيرة فقط؟
What is he doing?
ماذا يفعل؟
To the north of this place is mountains,
تقع الجبال شمال هذا المكان.
and the other 3 sides are surrounded by wilderness.
أما الجوانب الثلاثة الأخرى فهي محاطة بالبرية.
The west is clearly upwind,
من الواضح أن الغرب يقع في اتجاه الريح.
yet he ordered his men
لكنه أمر رجاله
to roast meat only on the south and east sides.
يُشوى اللحم فقط على الجانبين الجنوبي والشرقي.
It seems he wants to demoralize us first,
يبدو أنه يريد أن يحبطنا أولاً،
and then he has another move planned
ثم لديه خطة أخرى.
to lure the tiger from the mountain.
لجذب النمر من الجبل.
He wants us to step into
يريدنا أن ندخل
his carefully laid trap.
فخه المحكم.
He's got some brains.
إنه ذكي.
So you're the Heir Apparent?
إذن أنت الوريث الشرعي؟
This is for my grandma.
هذا من أجل جدتي.
Peasant.
فلاح.
How dare you—
كيف تجرؤ؟
If not for you little bastard,
لولاك أيها الوغد الصغير،
my mother wouldn't be paralyzed in bed.
لن تُصاب والدتي بالشلل في الفراش.
You scared her paralyzed.
لقد أرعبتها لدرجة أنها شلّت حركتها.
I wanted to go back in glory,
أردت العودة بمجد،
and stay by her side
وابقَ بجانبها
and be there for her end.
وأن أكون بجانبها في نهايتها.
Is there no end?
أليس هناك نهاية؟
My little sister is crippled.
أختي الصغيرة معاقة.
She should have had a better life.
كان ينبغي أن تحظى بحياة أفضل.
Because of you,
بفضلك،
her life is ruined.
حياتها مدمرة.
Is there no end?
أليس هناك نهاية؟
Enough!
كافٍ!
What did we people of Lin'an do wrong?
ما الخطأ الذي ارتكبناه نحن أهل لينآن؟
You didn't even give us a chance to live!
لم تمنحونا حتى فرصة للعيش!
Pigs want to live too.
الخنازير تريد أن تعيش أيضاً.
What's the use?
ما الفائدة؟
They still get slaughtered for meat.
لا تزال تُذبح للحصول على لحومها.
You lot
يا جماعة
can't even be compared to a pig.
لا يمكن مقارنته حتى بالخنزير.
You want to die, right?
أنت تريد الموت، أليس كذلك؟
Let me handle this.
دعني أتولى الأمر.
This stunt your wife is pulling
هذه الحيلة التي تقوم بها زوجتك
probably has Shi Yue all on edge.
ربما يكون هذا الأمر قد أثار قلق شي يو بشدة.
He won't be able to come up with any clever moves.
لن يتمكن من ابتكار أي تحركات ذكية.
It's reckless,
إنه تصرف متهور،
but it hit the mark by sheer luck.
لكنها أصابت الهدف بمحض الصدفة.
Shi Yue is naturally suspicious.
شي يو بطبيعتها شخصٌ متشكك.
Seeing this, he'll surely keep the main army back,
عند رؤية ذلك، سيُبقي الجيش الرئيسي في الخلف بالتأكيد.
and lead a small squad for a raid himself,
وقاد بنفسه فرقة صغيرة في غارة،
waiting for a chance to come up to get him himself.
ينتظر الفرصة المناسبة ليأتي ويقبض عليه بنفسه.
Come on.
تعال.
Hit me.
ضربني.
I like being hit by you.
أحب أن أتلقى الضربات منك.
Hit you?
هل ضربتك؟
That's letting you off too easy.
هذا تساهل كبير معك.
Gag him.
أسكته.
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
I haven't bathed in 5 days anyway.
لم أستحم منذ خمسة أيام على أي حال.
It's just a bit smelly.
رائحته كريهة بعض الشيء.
Give me a hand.
ساعدني.
Don't move.
.لا تتحرك
Stay still.
ابقَ ساكناً.
Stop moving.
توقف عن الحركة.
Rebels!
متمردون!
If you want to keep your Heir Apparent alive,
إذا كنت ترغب في إبقاء ولي عهدك على قيد الحياة،
you must trade meat and food for it!
يجب عليك مقايضة اللحوم والطعام مقابل ذلك!
They don't seem to hear us.
يبدو أنهم لا يسمعوننا.
If you want to save your Heir Apparent's life,
إذا كنت ترغب في إنقاذ حياة ولي عهدك،
bring salt and meat!
أحضر الملح واللحم!
I'm good at foreseeing things,
أنا بارع في استشراف الأمور،
but I really cannot figure
لكنني حقاً لا أستطيع أن أفهم
your wife out.
أخرج زوجتك.
Xie Wu, Xie Qi.
شيه وو، شيه تشي.
Stay here with me.
ابقَ هنا معي.
Xie Jiu.
شكرًا لك.
Go with the strategist to reinforce them immediately.
اذهب مع الاستراتيجي لتعزيزهم على الفور.
Yes, Sir.
نعم سيدي.
Ignoring us, huh? I'll whip you to death.
تتجاهلنا، أليس كذلك؟ سأجلدك حتى الموت.
Is that all you've got?
هل هذا كل ما لديك؟
You've been collecting debts for so long,
لقد كنتَ تجمع الديون لفترة طويلة،
haven't you saved up something nastier?
ألم تدخر شيئاً أسوأ؟
Something that could make someone die of anger.
شيء قد يدفع المرء إلى الموت من شدة الغضب.
Big Brother,
الأخ الأكبر،
didn't you tell us,
ألم تخبرنا؟
if they owe money and don't pay...
إذا كانوا مدينين بالمال ولم يسددوه...
Kick their ass all the way south?
هل تريد أن تسحقهم حتى تصل إلى الجنوب؟
Get him!
أمسك به!
The belt.
الحزام.
It's unnecessary.
هذا غير ضروري.
Come on.
تعال.
Let's do this.
هيا بنا نفعل ذلك.
Come on, show yourself.
هيا، أظهر نفسك.
Move it over there.
انقلها إلى هناك.
Come on.
تعال.
-Go.
انطلق.
Go.
يذهب.
Look closely, everyone!
انظروا جيداً يا جميعاً!
If you don't bring salt and meat,
إذا لم تحضر الملح واللحم،
I'll strip your Heir Apparent naked!
سأجرد ولي عهدك من ملابسه!
A warrior can be killed but not humiliated!
يمكن قتل المحارب ولكن لا يمكن إذلاله!
I'm really going to strip him!
سأجرده من ملابسه تماماً!
This is the Marquis of Wu'an's strategy to lure the enemy?
هل هذه هي استراتيجية ماركيز ووآن لاستدراج العدو؟
Wait.
انتظر.
Just wait a bit longer.
انتظر قليلاً.
If you don't bring salt and meat,
إذا لم تحضر الملح واللحم،
we'll strip your Heir Apparent naked!
سنجرد ولي عهدك من ملابسه!
Hurry up!
أسرع!
I'm really doing it!
أنا أفعل ذلك حقاً!
If you don't bring them,
إذا لم تحضرها،
your Heir Apparent won't have an heir anymore!
لن يكون لولي عهدك وريث بعد الآن!
Stop!
قف!
We'll do it.
سنفعل ذلك.
General!
عام!
Greetings, General.
تحية طيبة، أيها الجنرال.
General Shi Yue ordered us to deliver the meat and grain.
أمرنا الجنرال شي يو بتسليم اللحوم والحبوب.
What a coward.
يا له من جبان!
Do as they say!
افعل كما يقولون!
Don't hurt our Heir Apparent!
لا تؤذوا ولي عهدنا!
Put the stuff in the basket.
ضع الأغراض في السلة.
Don't try any tricks.
لا تحاول استخدام أي حيل.
Hurry.
عجل.
Pull it up.
ارفعه.
Okay.
تمام.
The one behind.
الشخص الذي في الخلف.
Coming. Hold on.
قادم. انتظر.
A full basket.
سلة مليئة.
Okay.
تمام.
Here.
هنا.
Don't worry about me!
لا تقلق علي!
Xie Zheng isn't here!
شيه تشنغ ليس هنا!
Kill these lowlifes for me!
اقتل هؤلاء الأوغاد من أجلي!
The Heir Apparent has ordered.
أصدر ولي العهد أوامره.
Kill!
قتل!
Kill them!
اقتلهم!
Hyah!
هيا!
Yes!
نعم!
-We have food. -We have provisions, bros.
لدينا طعام. لدينا مؤن يا إخوان.
-Great! -We won!
- رائع! - ​​لقد فزنا!
We're back.
لقد عدنا.
Let's go! Let's go!
هيا بنا! هيا بنا!
Okay.
تمام.
We're back.
لقد عدنا.
Great!
عظيم!
Look.
ينظر.
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
Take these 30 roasted sheep,
خذ هذه الأغنام الثلاثين المشوية،
[Oil]
[زيت]
50 dan of grain, 50 jin of salt,
50 دان من الحبوب، 50 جين من الملح،
and 3 barrels of oil
و3 براميل من النفط
to the Mess Crew.
إلى طاقم المطبخ.
Let everyone have a feast!
فليحتفل الجميع!
Great!
عظيم!
Fan is awesome!
المروحة رائعة!
More food!
المزيد من الطعام!
We're having a feast!
سنقيم وليمة!
[Oil]
[زيت]
Come on, move it here.
هيا، انقلها إلى هنا.
We did something big again.
لقد حققنا إنجازاً كبيراً مرة أخرى.
Will the Marquis of Wu'an reward us again?
هل سيكافئنا ماركيز ووآن مرة أخرى؟
I only want to ask the Marquis of Wu'an for one thing.
أريد فقط أن أطلب من ماركيز ووآن شيئًا واحدًا.
After we repel the enemy,
بعد أن نصد العدو،
hand over that dog Sui Yuanqing to us.
سلموا لنا ذلك الكلب سوي يوانكينغ.
Let us do whatever we want with him.
دعونا نفعل به ما نشاء.
Good!
جيد!
That's a good idea. Let's ask together.
هذه فكرة جيدة. فلنسأل معاً.
Let's do it.
هيا بنا نفعلها.
General Wu.
الجنرال وو.
Sui Yuanqing was exchanged for a lot of food.
تم استبدال سوي يوانكينغ بكمية كبيرة من الطعام.
Where is Yan Zheng?
أين يان تشنغ؟
There's lamb to help him recover.
يوجد لحم ضأن لمساعدته على التعافي.
Mrs. Fan, His Lordship wants to see you.
السيدة فان، يرغب صاحب السمو برؤيتك.
His Lordship wants to see us so soon?
هل يريد صاحب السمو رؤيتنا بهذه السرعة؟
What? Is there a reward?
ماذا؟ هل هناك مكافأة؟
Hand over your weapons first.
سلموا أسلحتكم أولاً.
Why do we have to hand over our weapons?
لماذا يتعين علينا تسليم أسلحتنا؟
No weapons are allowed in the tent.
ممنوع إدخال الأسلحة إلى الخيمة.
Here.
هنا.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Where is Yan Zheng?
أين يان تشنغ؟
After you see His Lordship,
بعد أن ترى صاحب السيادة،
you will see him.
ستراه.
Go.
يذهب.
Your Lordship, Fan Changyu and the others are here.
صاحب السمو، فان تشانغيو والآخرون هنا.
I am Fan Changyu.
أنا فان تشانغيو.
Greetings, Your Lordship.
تحية طيبة، يا صاحب السمو.
Fan Changyu!
فان تشانغيو!
You acted without permission.
لقد تصرفت بدون إذن.
According to the military rules,
وفقًا للقواعد العسكرية،
you should be severely punished.
يجب أن تُعاقب بشدة.
We act...
نتحرك...
Acted without orders?
هل تصرفت بدون أوامر؟
Your Lordship,
صاحب السعادة،
although we acted without orders,
على الرغم من أننا تصرفنا دون أوامر،
we also made a contribution.
لقد قدمنا ​​مساهمة أيضاً.
Please consider this, Your Lordship.
يرجى التفضل بالنظر في هذا الأمر، يا صاحب السعادة.
Since you are in the military camp,
بما أنك في المعسكر العسكري،
you must follow military rules.
يجب عليك اتباع القواعد العسكرية.
If I don't punish your unauthorized action today,
إذا لم أعاقبك على فعلك غير المصرح به اليوم،
you will only make bigger mistakes in the future.
سترتكب أخطاءً أكبر في المستقبل.
Fine!
بخير!
Then punish me alone!
ثم عاقبني وحدي!
I forced them to do it!
أجبرتهم على فعل ذلك!
No one forced us.
لم يجبرنا أحد.
We did it voluntarily!
لقد فعلنا ذلك طواعية!
If there is a punishment, we take it together.
إذا كان هناك عقاب، فإننا نتحمله معاً.
That's right!
هذا صحيح!
Yes!
نعم!
Your Lordship, we clearly earned military merit.
يا صاحب السعادة، لقد استحقينا بجدارة عسكرية بكل وضوح.
Fan Changyu was determined to get meat
كان فان تشانغيو مصمماً على الحصول على اللحم
to nourish the wounded soldiers.
لإطعام الجنود الجرحى.
Please consider this, Your Lordship.
يرجى التفضل بالنظر في هذا الأمر، يا صاحب السعادة.
-Please consider this, Your Lordship.
- أرجو منكم التفضل بالنظر في هذا الأمر، يا صاحب السعادة.
Your Lordship.
صاحب السعادة.
Yan Zheng implores Your Lordship again.
يناشد يان تشنغ سيادتكم مرة أخرى.
Fan Changyu is my wife.
فان تشانغيو هي زوجتي.
If she is to be punished,
إذا كان لا بد من معاقبتها،
I will bear it with her.
سأتحمل الأمر معها.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
You are injured.
أنت مصاب.
Don't talk nonsense.
لا تتفوه بالهراء.
According to article 27 of the military regulations,
وفقًا للمادة 27 من اللوائح العسكرية،
how much should one be punished
ما مقدار العقوبة المناسبة؟
for acting without orders?
بسبب التصرف بدون أوامر؟
Thirty flogs.
ثلاثون جلدة.
Considering Fan Changyu's merit in breaking the dam,
بالنظر إلى فضل فان تشانغيو في كسر السد،
her righteousness in transporting grain,
استقامتها في نقل الحبوب،
and that it is her first offense,
وأنها أول مخالفة لها،
the penalty shall be 20 strokes
تكون العقوبة 20 ضربة
as a warning to others.
كتحذير للآخرين.
Your Lordship,
صاحب السعادة،
please allow me
أرجو السماح لي
to be punished on behalf of my wife.
أن يُعاقب نيابة عن زوجتي.
No! No!
لا لا!
Your Lordship.
صاحب السعادة.
I'll take responsibility for my own actions.
سأتحمل مسؤولية أفعالي.
Just punish me alone.
عاقبني وحدي.
Please grant my request, Your Lordship.
أرجو منكم، يا صاحب السعادة، أن تستجيبوا لطلبي.
I... I...
أنا... أنا...
Your Lordship, I know I was wrong.
يا صاحب السعادة، أعلم أنني كنت مخطئاً.
My husband knows nothing about this.
زوجي لا يعلم شيئاً عن هذا.
Please punish me alone!
أرجوكم عاقبوني وحدي!
Th-Then tell me what I should do.
ثم أخبرني ماذا يجب أن أفعل.
Your Lordship should know,
ينبغي أن يعلم صاحب السمو،
military orders are absolute.
الأوامر العسكرية مطلقة.
Disobeying orders is a capital offense.
مخالفة الأوامر جريمة يعاقب عليها بالإعدام.
The Marquis of Wu'an should be fair in rewards and punishments.
ينبغي أن يكون ماركيز ووآن عادلاً في المكافآت والعقوبات.
Please give the order, Your Lordship.
يرجى إصدار الأمر، يا صاحب السعادة.
Punish only me.
عاقبني أنا فقط.
Your Lordship, punish me.
يا سيدي، عاقبني.
Your Lordship, punish us together.
يا صاحب السيادة، عاقبنا معاً.
Punish us together.
عاقبونا معاً.
Yes, we will take the punishment too.
نعم، سنتحمل العقاب أيضاً.
Military law is absolute.
القانون العسكري مطلق.
This is not a game.
هذه ليست لعبة.
Your Lordship!
يا صاحب السمو!
Give the order!
أصدر الأمر!
This isn't what we discussed.
هذا ليس ما ناقشناه.
Men!
الرجال!
Here!
هنا!
Execute the punishment on Yan Zheng alone.
نفذ العقوبة على يان تشنغ وحده.
Yes, Sir.
نعم سيدي.
Your Lordship!
يا صاحب السمو!
Proceed!
يتابع!
My husband really didn't know!
زوجي لم يكن يعلم حقاً!
Your Lordship!
يا صاحب السمو!
Get away!
ابتعد!